Guide to the Arnold Palmer advertisements and memorabilia, 1959-2005 and undated RL.11724
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Arnold Palmer advertisements and memorabilia
1959-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11724
0.2 Linear Feet
Professional golfer and celebrity spokesperson. Arnold Palmer advertisements and memorabilia collection consists of print advertisements featuring Palmer as spokesperson, celebrity figure or providing product endorsements, as well as print advertisements for Arnold Palmer's own companies. In addition, the collection includes trading and collector cards, telephone prepaid cards and photographs bearing Palmer's likeness. Companies represented include Beaunit, Chemstrand, Ford, Glaxo (Nicorette smoking cessation products), Haggar, Heinz, Munsingwear, Rayovac, Rockwell, Sears, United Air Lines and Wilson Sporting Goods. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Advertisements; Memorabilia
Biographical / Historical
Professional golfer and celebrity spokesperson. Arnold Palmer born 1929, Latrobe, Pa. U.S. Coast Guard 1951-1954; graduated Wake Forest College (now University) 1954; professional golfer 1954-1979; PGA Senior Tour 1980-2004; died 2016. Noted as the first professional golfer to amass $1 million in tour winnings, and the first golf superstar of the television era.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Arnold Palmer advertisements and memorabilia collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Anspach Travel Bureau collection of tourism literature
Bates Worldwide, Inc. records
Cause Marketing Forum. Halo Awards records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic advertisements collection
Rosenblatt window and store fashion displays
Collection Overview
Arnold Palmer advertisements and memorabilia collection consists of print advertisements featuring Palmer as spokesperson, celebrity figure or providing product endorsements, as well as print advertisements for Arnold Palmer's own companies. In addition, the collection includes trading and collector cards, telephone prepaid cards and photographs bearing Palmer's likeness. Companies represented include Beaunit, Chemstrand, Ford, Glaxo (Nicorette smoking cessation products), Haggar, Heinz, Munsingwear, Rayovac, Rockwell, Sears, United Air Lines and Wilson Sporting Goods. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States -- History; Celebrities; Endorsements in advertising; Palmer, Arnold, 1929-2016; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Ford Motor Company. Lincoln-Mercury Division; GlaxoSmithKline; H.J. Heinz Company; Rockwell International; Sears, Roebuck and Company; United Airlines
- Advertisements, 1959-2005 and undated; 1
  - APECO (American Photocopy Equipment Company), approximately 1967 (Box 1)
  - Arnold Palmer Company, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Arnold Palmer Golf Academy, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Arnold Palmer Golf Lesson video, undated (Box 1)
  - Beaunit Fibers (Vycron polyester), approximately 1963 (Box 1)
  - Bolens Orbit-Air lawn mower, approximately 1968 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Chemstrand (Acrilan), 1960 (Box 1)
  - Events, 1995, 2005 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Diners Club Matches; 66th Senior PGA Championship
  - Ford (Lincoln-Mercury)--Challenge Golf television program, 1963 (Box 1)
  - GlaxoSmithKline (Nicorette), 2002 (Box 1)
  - H.J. Heinz ketchup, approximately 1961 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Haggar slacks, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Munsingwear grand slam golf shirts, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Rayovac hearing aid batteries, 1993-1997 (Box 1)
  - Rayovac hearing aid batteries, 1990s (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Robert Bruce (Arnold Palmer line of golf shirts), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Rockwell circular saw, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Sears (Arnie Collection of sportswear), 1983 (Box 1)
  - Treesdale Golf and Country Club, 2003 (Box 1)
  - United Air Lines, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Wilson Sporting Goods (Dyna-Powered golf clubs, Wilson Staff golf ball), 1960-1961 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia, 1960s-2003; 2
  - Arnold Palmer 74th birthday tribute (Golf Magazine), 2003 (Box 1)
  - Collector cards, phone cards, etc., 1979-2001 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1960s-2003 (Box 1)